const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the advantage of fingerprinting?","answers":[{"option":"No special training required","bool":false},{"option":"It does not require any special and expensive instruments","bool":false},{"option":"It is applicable for all people","bool":false},{"option":"It is applicable for all age groups","bool":false},{"option":"It enables absolute identification of an individual","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following statements is true for euchromatin?","answers":[{"option":"Darkly stained chromatin material of non-dividing nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Chromosomal material confined to nucleolus","bool":false},{"option":"Chromatin material attached to nuclear membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrial DNA material used for self replication","bool":false},{"option":"Lightly stained chromatin material of non-dividing nuclei","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A person sees a purse on the ground while walking and wants to pick it up. Which of the following trunk movements will be required?","answers":[{"option":"Adduction","bool":false},{"option":"Supination","bool":false},{"option":"Flexion","bool":true},{"option":"Extension","bool":false},{"option":"Abduction","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A railway master, while traveling, saw a dead body that was cut into equal left and right halves. The body was cut in which anatomical plane?","answers":[{"option":"Transverse plane","bool":false},{"option":"Right paramedian plane","bool":false},{"option":"Coronal plane","bool":false},{"option":"Median sagittal plane","bool":true},{"option":"Left paramedian plane","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the advantage of administering drugs through the subcutaneous route?","answers":[{"option":"Fast releasing drugs are given subcutaneously","bool":false},{"option":"Gives immediate drug action","bool":false},{"option":"Slow releasing drugs are given subcutaneously","bool":false},{"option":"Gives a longer duration of action","bool":true},{"option":"Useful when patients are under anaphylactic shock","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is an abnormal chromosome with two identical arms, either two short (p) arms or two long (q) arms, called?","answers":[{"option":"Deletion","bool":false},{"option":"Insertion","bool":false},{"option":"Translocation","bool":false},{"option":"Ring chromosome","bool":false},{"option":"Isochromosome","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these is not present on the apical surface of epithelial cells?","answers":[{"option":"Cilia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemidesmosomes","bool":true},{"option":"Microvilli","bool":false},{"option":"Stereocilia","bool":false},{"option":"Receptors","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Apoptotic bodies undergoes which of the following phenomenon?","answers":[{"option":"Phagocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Organization","bool":false},{"option":"Mucoidization","bool":false},{"option":"Autolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Encapsulation","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Arachidonic acid becomes essential when which of the following is deficient in diet?","answers":[{"option":"Butyric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Linoleic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Lipoteichoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Palmitic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Linolenic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the effect of biotransformation on drugs?","answers":[{"option":"Less ionized","bool":false},{"option":"Less lipid soluble","bool":true},{"option":"More pharmacologically active","bool":false},{"option":"Less readily eliminated","bool":false},{"option":"More lipid soluble","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the branch of philosophy that deals with the moral aspect of human behavior?","answers":[{"option":"Ethics","bool":true},{"option":"Autonomy","bool":false},{"option":"Research ethics","bool":false},{"option":"Equity","bool":false},{"option":"Professional ethics","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"The diffusion potential of the cell membrane can be calculated using which of the following ions?","answers":[{"option":"Cl- only","bool":false},{"option":"Ca+ only","bool":false},{"option":"Several different ions","bool":true},{"option":"Na+ only","bool":false},{"option":"K+ only","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which cartilage is present in the walls of larger respiratory passages?","answers":[{"option":"Perichondrium","bool":false},{"option":"Chondro cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrocartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Elastic cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Hyaline cartilage","bool":true}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the cell membrane?","answers":[{"option":"Surrounds the nucleus in single layer","bool":false},{"option":"Contains proteins that only act as enzymes","bool":false},{"option":"Surrounds individual ribosome within the cell","bool":false},{"option":"It is structurally a lipid bilayer","bool":true},{"option":"It is maintained by vesicles derived from the smooth endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding spinal nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Ventral rami only have sensory fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal rami contain preganglionic sympathetic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal rami form plexuses","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed spinal nerves emerge from the intervertebral foramina","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsal root contains motor fiber","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is an example of elastic cartilage?","answers":[{"option":"Nasal cartilages","bool":false},{"option":"Pinna of ear","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Tracheal rings","bool":false},{"option":"Costal cartilages","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the main objective of the World Health Organization (WHO)'s healthy city initiative?","answers":[{"option":"Easy approach to health services","bool":false},{"option":"Better health and quality of life in cities","bool":true},{"option":"Provision of healthy diet to children","bool":false},{"option":"Free health services to geriatric population","bool":false},{"option":"Improved quality of maternity care services","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Mind, body, and soul are a part of which field of medicine?","answers":[{"option":"Dental","bool":false},{"option":"Psychiatry","bool":false},{"option":"Social","bool":false},{"option":"Holistic","bool":true},{"option":"Nuclear","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these is an essential fatty acid in the human diet?","answers":[{"option":"Palmitic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Butyric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Linoleic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Oleic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Acetic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following systems uses a feed-forward control principle?","answers":[{"option":"Nervous system","bool":true},{"option":"Renal system","bool":false},{"option":"Endocrine system","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiovascular system","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrointestinal system","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the cell cycle?","answers":[{"option":"G2 phase is the post mitotic phase","bool":true},{"option":"Centrosome replicates in the S phase of the cell cycle","bool":false},{"option":"Terminally differentiated cells are said to be permanently in G0 phase","bool":false},{"option":"In G1 phase cell volume increases","bool":false},{"option":"Rapidly dividing cells have shorter interphase direction","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following refers to the process that makes the drugs less effective?","answers":[{"option":"Oxidation","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphorylation","bool":false},{"option":"Biotransformation","bool":true},{"option":"Glycosylation","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogenation","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these is a sulfur-containing amino acid?","answers":[{"option":"Serine","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Alanine","bool":false},{"option":"Cysteine","bool":true},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"The amniotic cavity is formed within which cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Epiblast","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Amnioblast","bool":false},{"option":"Syncytiotrophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotrophoblast","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is an inappropriate statement regarding the plane synovial joint?","answers":[{"option":"Acromioclavicular joint belongs to this type","bool":false},{"option":"It is always a uniaxial joint","bool":true},{"option":"The articular surfaces are flat","bool":false},{"option":"Allows sliding or gliding movements","bool":false},{"option":"Do not have any axis of movement","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"In which of the following are four large complexes of the respiratory chain embedded?","answers":[{"option":"Cytoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrial matrix","bool":false},{"option":"Inner mitochondrial membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Inner membrane space","bool":false},{"option":"Outer mitochondrial membrane","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the function of the uterus?","answers":[{"option":"Host the developing sperm","bool":false},{"option":"Store of sperms","bool":false},{"option":"Host the developing ova","bool":false},{"option":"Host the developing fetus","bool":true},{"option":"Store of ova","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these is a semi-essential amino acid?","answers":[{"option":"Asparagine","bool":false},{"option":"Alanine","bool":false},{"option":"Arginine","bool":true},{"option":"Aspartate","bool":false},{"option":"Aspartic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Why are glucose and mannose epimers?","answers":[{"option":"They are mirror images of each other","bool":false},{"option":"Both are ketohexoses","bool":false},{"option":"One is pyranose and the other is furanose","bool":false},{"option":"Both are different in configuration around a single carbon","bool":true},{"option":"They rotate the plane polarized light in opposite direction","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following, along with amino sugars, constitutes the complex carbohydrates called glycosaminoglycans?","answers":[{"option":"Acetic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Ascorbic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Pantothenic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Uronic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Glutamic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the function of the Golgi complex?","answers":[{"option":"Steroid synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Lipid synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Protein synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Detoxification of organic molecules","bool":false},{"option":"Processing and packaging of organic molecules","bool":true}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Immunization falls under which level of prevention?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary","bool":false},{"option":"Primary","bool":true},{"option":"Treatment","bool":false},{"option":"Intervention","bool":false},{"option":"Tertiary","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is true for gametogenesis?","answers":[{"option":"Meiosis is the 1st step","bool":false},{"option":"No meiosis or mitosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitosis is the 1st step","bool":true},{"option":"Mitosis is the 2nd step","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"In a junctional complex, which cell junction lies in the most apical region of the cell?","answers":[{"option":"Macula occludens","bool":false},{"option":"Gap junction","bool":false},{"option":"Zonula occludens","bool":true},{"option":"Zonula adherens","bool":false},{"option":"Macula adherens","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these is true for semiconservative replication?","answers":[{"option":"Hybrid (old+new) DNA is formed","bool":true},{"option":"DNA polymerase III is used","bool":false},{"option":"No change occurs in parental duplex DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Does not occur normally","bool":false},{"option":"Fragments with new+old is present in both DNA duplexes","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following vitamins is required as a cofactor in collagen synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Niacin","bool":false},{"option":"Thiamine","bool":false},{"option":"Riboflavin","bool":false},{"option":"Ascorbic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Pantothenic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"In which one of the following steps of planning research, a researcher identifies that the objectives made for research are achieved?","answers":[{"option":"Evaluation","bool":true},{"option":"Priority setting","bool":false},{"option":"Outcome","bool":false},{"option":"Process","bool":false},{"option":"Objective","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"In which type of research does a researcher use facts or information already available and analyze it to make a critical evaluation of the material?","answers":[{"option":"Basic","bool":false},{"option":"Survey","bool":false},{"option":"Descriptive","bool":false},{"option":"Analytical","bool":true},{"option":"Systemic","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the role of lymphatic system?","answers":[{"option":"Production of antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Spread of neoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Spread of infection","bool":false},{"option":"Production of lymphocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Production of specific cells","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following shows signs of karyorrhexis, pyknosis, and karyolysis?","answers":[{"option":"Reversible cell injury","bool":false},{"option":"Necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Apoptosis","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty change","bool":false},{"option":"Cellular shrinkage","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"How do large macromolecules enter a cell?","answers":[{"option":"Pinocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Phagocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Exocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Endocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Transcytosis","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is the simplest unit of a living system?","answers":[{"option":"Multiple cells","bool":false},{"option":"Organs","bool":false},{"option":"Bones","bool":false},{"option":"Tissues","bool":false},{"option":"A single cell","bool":true}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Mutations in which of the following genes leads to Marfan syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"COL1A1, COL1A2","bool":false},{"option":"COL5A1, COL5A2","bool":false},{"option":"MSTN1, MSTN2","bool":false},{"option":"FBN1, FBN2 (high frequency in FBN1)","bool":true},{"option":"PTEN","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is not a microscopic feature of hyaline cartilages?","answers":[{"option":"Chondrocytes are arranged in longitudinal rows","bool":true},{"option":"Territorial matrix appears blue, due to the large amount of glycosaminoglycans","bool":false},{"option":"Perichondrium contains reserve cells","bool":false},{"option":"Chondrocytes are found in isogenous groups","bool":false},{"option":"No blood vessels enter in the substance of the cartilage","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following amino acids is used to synthesize niacin?","answers":[{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Histidine","bool":false},{"option":"Cysteine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Noncovalent modification after translation includes which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hydroxylation","bool":false},{"option":"Carboxylation","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphorylation","bool":false},{"option":"Glycosylation","bool":false},{"option":"Trimming of peptide chain","bool":true}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding optical isomers?","answers":[{"option":"They can rotate plane polarized light in the opposite direction","bool":false},{"option":"They are optically inactive","bool":true},{"option":"They are mirror images of each other","bool":false},{"option":"They possess L and D forms","bool":false},{"option":"They contain asymmetric carbon atoms","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following interactions are responsible for high viscosity, high surface tension, and high boiling point of water?","answers":[{"option":"Covalent bonds","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrophobic interactions","bool":false},{"option":"Electrostatic interactions","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen bonds","bool":true},{"option":"Van der Waals forces","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these is not included in posttranslational modification of proteins?","answers":[{"option":"Carboxylation","bool":false},{"option":"Splicing","bool":true},{"option":"Folding","bool":false},{"option":"Glycosylation","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphorylation","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the rapid reduction in the response of a drug after a single administration defined as?","answers":[{"option":"Anaphylaxis","bool":false},{"option":"Tachyphylaxis","bool":true},{"option":"Hypersensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Tolerance","bool":false},{"option":"Supersensitivity","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"The rate of diffusion through the cell membrane is proportional to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Molecular weight","bool":false},{"option":"ATP","bool":false},{"option":"Low temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Thickness of membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Concentration gradient","bool":true}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these statements is correct regarding anatomical planes of the human body?","answers":[{"option":"Transverse plane is not the only horizontal plane","bool":false},{"option":"All the planes are not imaginary","bool":false},{"option":"Median sagittal plane is at a right angle to parasagittal plane","bool":false},{"option":"Coronal plane is parallel to the transverse plane","bool":false},{"option":"Coronal plane divides the body into anterior and posterior halves","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is the inappropriate statement regarding blood vessels?","answers":[{"option":"The tunica intima delimits vessel wall on its outside","bool":true},{"option":"Tunica media is formed by a layer of circumferential smooth muscle and connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Tunica adventitia consists mainly of connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Tunica media delimits the adventitia from intima","bool":false},{"option":"The walls of the blood vessel is divided into three layers of tunics","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is true regarding the composition of a spinal nerve?","answers":[{"option":"It is formed by motor root only","bool":false},{"option":"It is formed by sensory root only","bool":false},{"option":"It is present only in the cervical region","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory fibers relay in ventral root","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal root relays sensory fibers","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the terms of movements?","answers":[{"option":"Extension is increasing the angle between bones or parts of the body","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsiflexion is moving the body forward","bool":false},{"option":"Extension is decreasing the angle between bones or body parts","bool":false},{"option":"Flexion is increasing the angle between bones or parts of the body","bool":false},{"option":"Plantar flexion is moving the foot off the ground","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the anatomical planes?","answers":[{"option":"Sagittal planes are horizontal planes","bool":false},{"option":"Coronal and sagittal planes are horizontal planes","bool":false},{"option":"Coronal and sagittal planes are vertical planes","bool":true},{"option":"Mid sagittal plane is at right angle to the sagittal plane","bool":false},{"option":"Coronal plane divides the body into right and left halves","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A 31-year-old woman comes to the outpatient department (OPD) with a history of 4 months of amenorrhea. Upon investigation, the height of the fundus is found to be 16 weeks. There is a medical history of hemophilia. Which investigation method should be used by the obstetrician?","answers":[{"option":"Fetoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-fetoprotein (AFP) serum test","bool":false},{"option":"Chorionic villus sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Amniocentesis","bool":true},{"option":"Ultrasonography","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"In meiosis, four daughter cells are produced with an \"n\" number of chromosomes. The \"n\" number corresponds to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Diploid","bool":false},{"option":"Triploid","bool":false},{"option":"Aneuploid","bool":false},{"option":"Euploid","bool":false},{"option":"Haploid","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"On microscope examination of a cell, no nuclear membranes are seen. The chromosomes are lined up at the \"equatorial plate.\" Which phase of mitosis is seen?","answers":[{"option":"Prophase","bool":false},{"option":"Anaphase","bool":false},{"option":"Metaphase","bool":true},{"option":"Telophase","bool":false},{"option":"Cytokinesis","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following descriptions of the anatomical position is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Squatting position, both arms by side, and both feet inverted","bool":false},{"option":"Standing straight, face forward, arms by the side and flexed","bool":false},{"option":"Standing straight, both arms abducted, both feet together","bool":false},{"option":"Standing straight, both arms by the side, and both feet together","bool":true},{"option":"Standing straight, both arms by the side and feet everted","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Sterilization by filtration can be used to leave out spores and bacteria. This method is used for which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Venipunctures","bool":false},{"option":"Surgical equipment","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture samples","bool":false},{"option":"Fecal samples","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous (IV) fluids","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"DNA is replicated during which phase?","answers":[{"option":"G1 phase","bool":false},{"option":"S phase","bool":true},{"option":"G0 phase","bool":false},{"option":"Mitosis","bool":false},{"option":"G2 phase","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following statements regarding cell organelles is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Centrioles can easily be seen under light microscope","bool":false},{"option":"Nuclear membrane is double plasma membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Golgi complex is found in all body cells","bool":false},{"option":"Genetic material is found in nucleolus","bool":false},{"option":"Lysosomal enzymes are active at high pH","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Histamine is released from basophilic granules of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Mast cells","bool":true},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Adipocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma cells","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Rough endoplasmic reticulum is involved in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Lipid synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Detoxification of organic molecules","bool":false},{"option":"Steroid synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Packaging of secretory granules","bool":false},{"option":"Protein synthesis","bool":true}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these is true regarding the cell surface modifications?","answers":[{"option":"Each cilium contains a central bundle of 20 to 30 actin filaments","bool":false},{"option":"Each flagellum has a wall of nine-doublet microtubules","bool":true},{"option":"Stereocilia are in fact very long microvilli which lack central microfilament bundle","bool":false},{"option":"Each stereocilium has a wall of nine-triplet microtubules","bool":false},{"option":"Each microvillus contains two central microtubules, surrounded by 9 circularly arranged peripheral doublets of microtubules","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the simple sequence of amino acid called?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary structure","bool":false},{"option":"Primary structure","bool":true},{"option":"Tertiary structure","bool":false},{"option":"Folding structure","bool":false},{"option":"Quaternary structure","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the central nervous system made up of?","answers":[{"option":"Brain and spinal cord","bool":true},{"option":"Brain stem and spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrum and brain stem","bool":false},{"option":"Brain and cranial nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrum and cerebellum","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these is false regarding the chromatin?","answers":[{"option":"It is a combination of RNA, histones and other proteins that makes up chromosome","bool":true},{"option":"It is found inside the nuclei of eukaryotic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Heterochromatin is more compact form of DNA","bool":false},{"option":"The structure of chromosomes and chromatin varies throughout the cell cycle","bool":false},{"option":"Euchromatin is less compact form of DNA","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these is a correct statement regarding microscopy?","answers":[{"option":"Condenser lens amplifies the image of the object","bool":false},{"option":"Objective lens not only enlarges but also clears the image of the object","bool":true},{"option":"Ocular lens produce a cone of light to illuminate the object to be observed","bool":false},{"option":"Resolving power means ability to enlarge the image","bool":false},{"option":"Magnifying power means ability to clearly separate two particles situated close together","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the coupled transport of two different molecules in opposite directions called?","answers":[{"option":"Uniport","bool":false},{"option":"Cotransport","bool":false},{"option":"Biport","bool":false},{"option":"Symport","bool":false},{"option":"Antiport","bool":true}]},{"id":71,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the mode of transmission of the diseases which are carried by women while exhibited by men?","answers":[{"option":"Chromosomal disorders","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Polygenic disorders","bool":false},{"option":"Sex linked inheritance","bool":true},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the dominant cell type in the lymph follicle?","answers":[{"option":"B lymphocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma cells","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular cells","bool":false},{"option":"T lymphocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these is false for endocrine glands?","answers":[{"option":"Their secretions are called hormones","bool":false},{"option":"They have ductless glands","bool":false},{"option":"Do not contain intracellular vacuole","bool":true},{"option":"Pour their secretions directly into blood","bool":false},{"option":"Their secretions are regulated by feedback loops","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these enzymes is used for the formation of hydroxyproline?","answers":[{"option":"Prolinelyase","bool":false},{"option":"Prolyl oxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxylyase","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Prolyl hydroxylase","bool":true}]},{"id":75,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Gastrulation is the process involving the conversion of the bilaminar disc to trilaminar disc. Which is the first morphological sign for gastrulation?","answers":[{"option":"Development of neural tube","bool":false},{"option":"Development of neural plate","bool":false},{"option":"Development of notochord","bool":false},{"option":"Development of prechordal plate","bool":false},{"option":"Development of primitive streak","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is not a connective tissue cell?","answers":[{"option":"Fibroblast","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophage","bool":false},{"option":"Reticulocyte","bool":true},{"option":"Plasma cell","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is the inappropriate structure regarding peripheral nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Endoneurium","bool":false},{"option":"Nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Tracts","bool":true},{"option":"Schwann cells","bool":false},{"option":"Ganglia","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the intracellular fluid volume in the human body?","answers":[{"option":"28 litres","bool":true},{"option":"10 litres","bool":false},{"option":"35 litres","bool":false},{"option":"25 litres","bool":false},{"option":"20 litres","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the major component of most connective tissues?","answers":[{"option":"Laminin","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrils","bool":false},{"option":"Elastin","bool":false},{"option":"Proteoglycan","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen","bool":true}]},{"id":80,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which is the only structure that receives a parasympathetic supply?","answers":[{"option":"Suprarenal medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral blood vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchi","bool":true},{"option":"Sweat glands","bool":false},{"option":"Limbs","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"The parasympathetic neurons originate from which part of the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Coccygeal","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic","bool":false},{"option":"Sacral","bool":true},{"option":"Cervical","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Where are the preganglionic sympathetic neurons in the grey matter of the spinal cord found?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral horn","bool":true},{"option":"Spinal canal","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior horn","bool":false},{"option":"Grey matter around spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior horn","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the role of Sertoli cells in spermatogenesis?","answers":[{"option":"Replicate type A spermatogonia","bool":false},{"option":"Attach to basal lamina","bool":false},{"option":"Providing a population of type B spermatogonia","bool":false},{"option":"Isolate gamete cells","bool":true},{"option":"Form the junctional complex","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which is true for the secondary cartilaginous joints?","answers":[{"option":"Manubriosternal joint belongs to this group","bool":true},{"option":"The joint cavity exists frequently","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior tibiofibular joint is an example of this variety","bool":false},{"option":"They are freely mobile","bool":false},{"option":"The articular surfaces are covered by the hyaline cartilage","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A significant loss of genetic material is observed in which of the following chromosomal structure alteration?","answers":[{"option":"Inversion (paracentric)","bool":false},{"option":"Fusion of telomeres in ring chromosome","bool":false},{"option":"Isochrome","bool":false},{"option":"Inversion (pericentric)","bool":false},{"option":"Unbalanced translocation","bool":true}]},{"id":86,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these statements regarding the sodium-potassium (Na+/K+) ATPase pump is correct?","answers":[{"option":"It is important to maintain constant cell volume","bool":true},{"option":"It is an ionic channel passing ions through diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Uses the energy produced by the potassium","bool":false},{"option":"It moves 3Na+ inside the cell and 2K+ outside the cell","bool":false},{"option":"It is not inhibited by metabolic posions","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the total range of thickness of the cell membrane as measured from an electron microphotograph?","answers":[{"option":"5-11 nm","bool":false},{"option":"7.5-10 nm","bool":true},{"option":"4-10 nm","bool":false},{"option":"2.5-4 nm","bool":false},{"option":"3-5 nm","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Why is topoisomerase required in DNA replication?","answers":[{"option":"Unwinds the duplex DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Relieves the torsional strain","bool":true},{"option":"Seals the nick","bool":false},{"option":"Stabilizes single stranded unwound DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Polymerizes the lagging strand of DNA","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Triacylglycerols are esters of fatty acid with which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Methanol","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol","bool":false},{"option":"Glycerol","bool":true},{"option":"Ethanol","bool":false},{"option":"Sphingomyelin","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Why can water dissolve large quantities of salts?","answers":[{"option":"More cations","bool":false},{"option":"Strong dipolar structure","bool":true},{"option":"More anions","bool":false},{"option":"Weak dipolar structure","bool":false},{"option":"Neutral pH","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"When a membrane is permeable to several different ions, which of these is used to calculate diffusion potential?","answers":[{"option":"Diffusion equation","bool":false},{"option":"Nernst equation","bool":false},{"option":"Threshold equation","bool":false},{"option":"Transmission equation","bool":false},{"option":"Goldman–Hodgkin–Katz equation","bool":true}]},{"id":92,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which enzyme does not belong to the class hydrolases?","answers":[{"option":"Phosphatases","bool":false},{"option":"Esterases","bool":false},{"option":"Peptidases","bool":false},{"option":"Disaccharidases","bool":false},{"option":"Synthases","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is responsible for the ischemia-reperfusion injury?","answers":[{"option":"Increased generation of oxygen free radicals","bool":true},{"option":"Protein cross linking","bool":false},{"option":"Deficiency of respiratory cytosolic chain enzymes","bool":false},{"option":"Lipid peroxidation of membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Activation of cytosolic enzymes","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following chemicals causes direct cell injury?","answers":[{"option":"Mercuric chloride","bool":true},{"option":"Carbon tetrachloride","bool":false},{"option":"Helium","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium chloride","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following disorders occur due to DNA changes in the coding region?","answers":[{"option":"Fragile X syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Huntington disease","bool":true},{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Friedrich ataxia","bool":false},{"option":"Myotonic dystrophy","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following structures is innervated by preganglionic sympathetic nerve fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Pancreas","bool":false},{"option":"Heart","bool":false},{"option":"Lung","bool":false},{"option":"Skeletal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenal medulla","bool":true}]},{"id":97,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following structures is not a part of the peripheral nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Cranial nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":true},{"option":"Autonomic nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal ganglia","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is a nonreducing sugar?","answers":[{"option":"Mannose","bool":false},{"option":"Sucrose","bool":true},{"option":"Fructose","bool":false},{"option":"Maltose","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following lymphatic tissues have afferent lymph vessels?","answers":[{"option":"Tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Mucosa associated lymphoid tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Thymus","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following research steps is related to the implication of the research findings?","answers":[{"option":"Communication of research results","bool":true},{"option":"Formulation of objective","bool":false},{"option":"Data collection","bool":false},{"option":"Developing research proposal","bool":false},{"option":"Conducting the study","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which type of adaptation is seen in Barrett's esophagus?","answers":[{"option":"Anaplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Metaplasia","bool":true}]},{"id":102,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which type of RNA contains pseudo uracil?","answers":[{"option":"tRNA","bool":false},{"option":"Both tRNA + rRNA","bool":true},{"option":"rRNA","bool":false},{"option":"mRNA","bool":false},{"option":"Both rRNA + mRNA","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the cause of Laron dwarfism?","answers":[{"option":"Radiation injury","bool":false},{"option":"IGF-1 deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone receptor mutation","bool":true},{"option":"Pituitary tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Head injury","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following processes requires energy?","answers":[{"option":"Phagocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Filtration","bool":false},{"option":"Simple diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Diffusion","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is true for unsaturated fatty acids?","answers":[{"option":"High degree of saturation","bool":false},{"option":"Remains solid at room temperature","bool":false},{"option":"High melting point","bool":false},{"option":"Low melting point","bool":true},{"option":"High hydrophilic character","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A person loses sensation at the anterior surface of the forearm. The neurons involved in the transmission of signals from here to the central nervous system are of which type?","answers":[{"option":"Motor neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Interneuron","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudounipolar","bool":true},{"option":"Bipolar","bool":false},{"option":"Multipolar","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Lymphatics vessels are present in which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Bone marrow","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsils","bool":true},{"option":"Eye ball","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A person loses the sensation of foot due to the injury to the foot. He also has diabetes. Foot belongs to which part of the lower limb?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral","bool":false},{"option":"Superior","bool":false},{"option":"Medial","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal","bool":false},{"option":"Distal","bool":true}]},{"id":109,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Gaseous sterilization is the subtype of which type of sterilization?","answers":[{"option":"Physical","bool":false},{"option":"Chemical","bool":true},{"option":"Dry heat","bool":false},{"option":"Moist heat","bool":false},{"option":"Liquid","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A bowler had pain in a diseased shoulder while bowling. What type of joint is the shoulder joint?","answers":[{"option":"Saddle joint","bool":false},{"option":"Condyloid","bool":false},{"option":"Hinge joint","bool":false},{"option":"Ball and socket joint","bool":true},{"option":"Gliding joint","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following takes part in the regulation of gene expression?","answers":[{"option":"rRNA","bool":false},{"option":"tRNA","bool":false},{"option":"ssRNA","bool":false},{"option":"mRNA","bool":false},{"option":"miRNA","bool":true}]},{"id":112,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the complex of proteins and filaments which span the entire cell and is responsible for giving the shape to the cell called?","answers":[{"option":"Plasma proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Cytoskeleton","bool":true},{"option":"Cytosol","bool":false},{"option":"Centrioles","bool":false},{"option":"Connective tissue","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the function of beta carotene in relation to vitamin A?","answers":[{"option":"Trans retinol","bool":false},{"option":"Provitamin","bool":true},{"option":"Substrate","bool":false},{"option":"Steroid","bool":false},{"option":"Coenzyme","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A first-year medical student was nervous when taking their viva exam. How will this student's autonomic nervous system respond?","answers":[{"option":"Increased heart rate","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchoconstriction","bool":false},{"option":"Vasoconstriction","bool":false},{"option":"Constriction of pupil","bool":false},{"option":"Increased gastrointestinal mobility","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"In prokaryotes, the mechanism of rho independent termination of DNA replication involves which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hogness box","bool":false},{"option":"-35 sequence","bool":false},{"option":"Pribnow box","bool":false},{"option":"TATA box","bool":false},{"option":"GC rich hairpin loop","bool":true}]},{"id":116,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these is not a type of fibrous joint?","answers":[{"option":"temporo-parietal suture","bool":false},{"option":"Gomphosis","bool":false},{"option":"Synchondrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Syndesmosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lambdoid suture","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of these is true for circumduction?","answers":[{"option":"Involves ball and socket joints only","bool":false},{"option":"Involves flexion/extension and medial/lateral rotation","bool":false},{"option":"Involves abduction/adduction and medial/lateral rotation","bool":false},{"option":"Involves only one axis of rotation","bool":false},{"option":"Involves abduction/adduction and flexion/extension","bool":true}]},{"id":118,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which squamous epithelium is present in blood vessels?","answers":[{"option":"Stratified squamous nonkeratinized epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelium","bool":true},{"option":"Mesothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous keratinized epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Transitional epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding capillaries?","answers":[{"option":"Present in epidermis","bool":true},{"option":"Site of exchange of nutrients and oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"Connect arterioles to venules","bool":false},{"option":"Contain endothelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Absent in cornea","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which neurotransmitter is released at preganglionic and postganglionic nerve terminals of the parasympathetic nervous system respectively?","answers":[{"option":"Acetylcholine and norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine and acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine and acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine and epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine and acetylcholine","bool":true}]},{"id":121,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Enzymes that use ATP as a substrate or cofactor require which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Fe","bool":false},{"option":"Ca+2","bool":false},{"option":"Mn+2","bool":false},{"option":"Mg+2","bool":true},{"option":"Sulphur","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the formula for the calculation of the volume distribution of drugs?","answers":[{"option":"Vd= plasma concentration + dose","bool":false},{"option":"Vd = 2 x plasma concentration / dose","bool":false},{"option":"Vd = plasma concentration × dose","bool":false},{"option":"Vd = Plasma concentration / dose","bool":false},{"option":"Vd = administered dose / plasma concentration","bool":true}]},{"id":123,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"The gain of a control system is calculated by which formula?","answers":[{"option":"Gain= +feedback / -ve feedback","bool":false},{"option":"Gain = correction - error","bool":false},{"option":"Gain= error / correction","bool":false},{"option":"Gain = correction / error","bool":true},{"option":"Gain= -feedback / +ve feedback","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the activated form of vitamin B12?","answers":[{"option":"Coenzyme A","bool":false},{"option":"Retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Pyridoxal phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Pantothenic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Methyl cobalamin","bool":true}]},{"id":125,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A person died from tuberculosis. After his death, a tissue biopsy was performed and yellow cream cheese-like, friable mass was observed in the lungs. Which of the following necrosis is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Gangrenous","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinoid","bool":false},{"option":"Caseous","bool":true},{"option":"Coagulative","bool":false},{"option":"Liquefactive","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Who took the Healthy City Initiative?","answers":[{"option":"United Nations International Children's Emergency Fund","bool":false},{"option":"World Health Organization","bool":true},{"option":"United Nations","bool":false},{"option":"United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization","bool":false},{"option":"World Health Assembly","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which type of enzymes transfers functional groups?","answers":[{"option":"Lyases","bool":false},{"option":"Oxidases","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxylases","bool":false},{"option":"Transferases","bool":true},{"option":"Hydrolases","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following epithelium is found in the distal convoluted tubules of the kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Simple cuboidal","bool":true},{"option":"Simple columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous","bool":false},{"option":"Simple squamous","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Tyrosine falls under which class of amino acids?","answers":[{"option":"Acidic","bool":false},{"option":"Simple","bool":false},{"option":"Non-essential","bool":true},{"option":"Basic","bool":false},{"option":"Essential","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which RNA can stop the expression of the gene when introduced synthetically?","answers":[{"option":"Short interfering RNA","bool":true},{"option":"rRNA","bool":false},{"option":"miRNA","bool":false},{"option":"PreRNA","bool":false},{"option":"Long interfering RNA","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"An organism (for example bacteria, virus, or parasite) rises in a person's body in such a way that it does not cause harm but is transferred to another person and can cause infection. This phase is termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Log phase","bool":false},{"option":"Carrier phase","bool":true},{"option":"Stationary phase","bool":false},{"option":"Mobile phase","bool":false},{"option":"Transient phase","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which process occurs in phase 2 of biotransformation?","answers":[{"option":"Acetylation","bool":true},{"option":"Reduction","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Oxidation","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphorylation","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Alcohol is used in which type of sterilization?","answers":[{"option":"Moist heat","bool":false},{"option":"Liquid","bool":false},{"option":"Physical","bool":false},{"option":"Chemical","bool":true},{"option":"Gaseous","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A girl was brought to the hospital after she fell while playing and could not move her knee. After examination, it was told that the joint between the epiphysis and diaphysis of the tibia has been dislocated. Which type of joint is it?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrous","bool":false},{"option":"Gomphosis","bool":false},{"option":"Primary cartilaginous (synchondroses)","bool":true},{"option":"Synovial","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary cartilaginous (symphysis)","bool":false}]},{"id":135,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the function of DNA ligase?","answers":[{"option":"Removes torsional strain","bool":false},{"option":"Unwinds DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Excises base pairs","bool":false},{"option":"Repairs DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Joins DNA molecules","bool":true}]},{"id":136,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following does not have a synapase?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal root ganglion","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior horn of spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Cell bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic chain ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Dendrites","bool":false}]},{"id":137,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Activation of which of these leads to the generation of an action potential?","answers":[{"option":"Voltage gated K channel","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium leaky channel","bool":false},{"option":"Na/K ATPase pump","bool":false},{"option":"Voltage gated Na channel","bool":true},{"option":"Tandem domain channels","bool":false}]},{"id":138,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A histopathologist observed simple cuboidal epithelium on a slide. Simple cuboidal epithelium covers which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Surface of ovary","bool":true},{"option":"Rectum","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney","bool":false}]},{"id":139,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A patient has undergone colonoscopy and esophagoscopy. Cells collected in the biopsy are of non-keratinized stratified squamous epithelium. Which structure contains these cells?","answers":[{"option":"Colon","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Sigmoid column","bool":false},{"option":"Rectum","bool":false},{"option":"Esophagus","bool":true}]},{"id":140,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A cricket player while playing felt difficulty in bowling due to a diseased shoulder joint. Which of the following is true for the movement of shoulder joint?","answers":[{"option":"Pivot","bool":false},{"option":"Biaxial","bool":false},{"option":"Condyloid","bool":false},{"option":"Uniaxial","bool":false},{"option":"Multiaxial","bool":true}]},{"id":141,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following RNA is involved in the catalyzation of the reaction and bringing about self-splicing of introns?","answers":[{"option":"Small nuclear ribonucleoproteins","bool":true},{"option":"Spliceosome 14","bool":false},{"option":"Ribozyme","bool":false},{"option":"miRNA","bool":false},{"option":"tRNA","bool":false}]},{"id":142,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Sacrococcygeal teratoma occurs due to remains of the primitive streak in postnatal life. Primitive streak formation is the first sign of which of these stages?","answers":[{"option":"Cleavage","bool":false},{"option":"Blastulation","bool":false},{"option":"Neurulation","bool":false},{"option":"Implantation","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrulation","bool":true}]},{"id":143,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"The student is given a histological section of the gray matter of the brain to observe. The\r\nimage shows cells with multiple cytoplasmic processes spread across. These perivascular cells\r\nalso sit at various places along the capillary endothelium. Which cells are these?","answers":[{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Microglia","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Protoplasmic astrocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Fibrous astrocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":144,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the reason for the presence of cleavage lines in the skin (also called Langer lines)?","answers":[{"option":"Direction of elastic fibers in dermis","bool":false},{"option":"Junctions between superficial and deep fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Direction of collagen fibers in dermis","bool":true},{"option":"Fingerprints","bool":false},{"option":"Skin creases over joints","bool":false}]},{"id":145,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Intervention is an important step in which of the following research?","answers":[{"option":"Basic","bool":false},{"option":"Applied","bool":false},{"option":"Experimental","bool":true},{"option":"Observe","bool":false},{"option":"Empirical","bool":false}]},{"id":146,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"In prenatal diagnosis, which is the non-invasive method?","answers":[{"option":"Amniocentesis","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal serum alpha fetoprotein test","bool":true},{"option":"Cordocentesis","bool":false},{"option":"Chorionic villus sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Pre implantation genetic diagnosis","bool":false}]},{"id":147,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which type of mutation leads to the addition of a different amino acid in the sequence?","answers":[{"option":"Missense mutation","bool":true},{"option":"Frame shift mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Base substitution mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Nonsense mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Point mutation","bool":false}]},{"id":148,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What are macrophages in connective tissue known as?","answers":[{"option":"Langerhans cell","bool":false},{"option":"Kupffer cell","bool":false},{"option":"Histiocyte","bool":true},{"option":"Dust cell","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma cell","bool":false}]},{"id":149,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Glycogen and starch are polymers of which of the following monosaccharides?","answers":[{"option":"L-glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-D-glucose","bool":true},{"option":"Galactose","bool":false},{"option":"Fructose","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-D-glucose","bool":false}]},{"id":150,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A 30-year-old man came to a hospital with the complaint of loss of proprioception at the joint. According to Hilton's law, the diseased nerve was not supplying which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Joint ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Joint capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilage","bool":true},{"option":"Skin","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle","bool":false}]},{"id":151,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which type of starch has both α 1-4 linkages and α 1-6 linkages (at branch points)?","answers":[{"option":"Modified starch","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Cellulose","bool":false},{"option":"Amylopectin","bool":true},{"option":"Amylose","bool":false}]},{"id":152,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"In the healthcare system, which type of research is conducted with a scientific approach using two sets of variables of control and a study group?","answers":[{"option":"Experimental","bool":true},{"option":"Observational","bool":false},{"option":"Empirical","bool":false},{"option":"Applied","bool":false},{"option":"Basic","bool":false}]},{"id":153,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which type of connective tissue is found in the capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Dense irregular connective tissue","bool":true},{"option":"Reticular connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Dense regular connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Loose areolar connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false}]},{"id":154,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which polymer found in plant cells is a major component of their cell and is also a major constituent of insoluble dietary fiber?","answers":[{"option":"Chitin","bool":false},{"option":"Glycogen","bool":false},{"option":"Dextrin","bool":false},{"option":"Starch","bool":false},{"option":"Cellulose","bool":true}]},{"id":155,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A dense connective tissue containing bundles of collagen fibers that run parallel to each other and have only fibroblast cells with flattened nuclei in between them. This tissue is present in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Adipose tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Tendon","bool":true}]},{"id":156,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which is the effect of parasympathetic stimulation?","answers":[{"option":"Increased heart rate","bool":false},{"option":"Vasoconstriction","bool":false},{"option":"Increased blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Vasodilation","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary constriction","bool":true}]},{"id":157,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which morphology is related to irreversible cell injury?","answers":[{"option":"Blebbing of cytoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty change","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Removal of ribosomes from the endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Cellular swelling","bool":false}]},{"id":158,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Secondary active transport uses energy from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Movement due to high gradient of Na+ ions outside","bool":true},{"option":"Breakdown of glycogen","bool":false},{"option":"ATP","bool":false},{"option":"ADP","bool":false},{"option":"Movement of glucose/amino acid","bool":false}]},{"id":159,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"During collagen synthesis, what does the formation of hydroxyproline residues require?","answers":[{"option":"Ascorbic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Thiamine","bool":false},{"option":"Retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Methyl cobalamin","bool":false},{"option":"Pyridoxal phosphate","bool":false}]},{"id":160,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"In which type of inhibition do a substance bind to the active site and the substrate compete with that substance to occupy the active site?","answers":[{"option":"Uncompetitive inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Allosteric inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Competitive inhibition","bool":true},{"option":"Non-competitive inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Irreversible inhibition","bool":false}]},{"id":161,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What causes hyperpolarization during an action potential?","answers":[{"option":"Prolonged opening of voltage gated K+ channels","bool":true},{"option":"Prolonged opening of voltage gated sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Closure of Cl- channels","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium leaky channels","bool":false},{"option":"Prolonged closure of K+ ion channels","bool":false}]},{"id":162,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the advantage of the parenteral route?","answers":[{"option":"Greater absorption than oral route","bool":true},{"option":"Cannot be given to unconscious patients","bool":false},{"option":"Cannot be used in emergency","bool":false},{"option":"Takes time to reach the site of action","bool":false},{"option":"Delayed access to systematic circulation","bool":false}]},{"id":163,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Some bacteria cause respiratory tract infections. Which structure in bacteria is responsible for adherence to the respiratory tract?","answers":[{"option":"Teichoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmid","bool":false},{"option":"Glycocalyx","bool":false},{"option":"Pili","bool":true},{"option":"Proteoglycan","bool":false}]},{"id":164,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which is the major glycoprotein of the extracellular matrix that is also soluble in plasma?","answers":[{"option":"Elastin","bool":false},{"option":"Fibronectin","bool":true},{"option":"Proteoglycan","bool":false},{"option":"Laminin","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen","bool":false}]},{"id":165,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A histologist observed a cut section of the umbilical cord under a microscope and saw\r\na substance called the Wharton's jelly. This substance consists of which tissue?","answers":[{"option":"Dense regular connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Mesenchyme","bool":false},{"option":"Extraembryonic mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Mucoid tissue","bool":true},{"option":"Dense irregular connective tissue","bool":false}]},{"id":166,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the ability of a drug to produce a response called?","answers":[{"option":"Bioavailibilty","bool":false},{"option":"Efficacy","bool":false},{"option":"Kinematics","bool":false},{"option":"Potency","bool":false},{"option":"Intrinsic activity","bool":true}]},{"id":167,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"A child comes with deformed and shortened long bones of lower limbs. The deformed bones are not ossified by which ossification?","answers":[{"option":"Cartilaginous ossification","bool":true},{"option":"Primary centre","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary ossification centre","bool":false},{"option":"Endochondral ossification","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":168,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Maltose is classified as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Non modified starch","bool":false},{"option":"Monosaccharide","bool":false},{"option":"Polyol","bool":false},{"option":"Oligosaccharide","bool":false},{"option":"Disaccharide","bool":true}]},{"id":169,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Beta-pleated sheat in an example of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Quaternary structure","bool":false},{"option":"Primary structure","bool":false},{"option":"Tertiary structure","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary structure","bool":true},{"option":"Linear structure","bool":false}]},{"id":170,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which is the signaling molecule made from the oxidation of arachidonic acid or other polyunsaturated fats?","answers":[{"option":"Phosphlipid","bool":false},{"option":"Eicosanoid","bool":true},{"option":"Triacylglycerol","bool":false},{"option":"Steroid","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol","bool":false}]},{"id":171,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"pH of buffer mainly depends on which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Conjugated acid","bool":false},{"option":"Concentration of H+ (acid) and its conjugate base","bool":true},{"option":"Strength of H+","bool":false},{"option":"Conjugated base","bool":false},{"option":"Concentration of OH-","bool":false}]},{"id":172,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is added to the 5'-prime end of mRNA in eukaryotes?","answers":[{"option":"S-adenosyl methionine","bool":false},{"option":"Methionine","bool":false},{"option":"7-methylguanosine cap","bool":true},{"option":"Poly-A tail","bool":false},{"option":"GC rich hairpin loop","bool":false}]},{"id":173,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which is the branch of moral psychology?","answers":[{"option":"Research ethics","bool":false},{"option":"Ethics","bool":true},{"option":"Duty-based ethic","bool":false},{"option":"Professional ethics","bool":false},{"option":"Virtue ethics","bool":false}]},{"id":174,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"3D folding of protein due to side-chain interaction is classified as which structure of a protein?","answers":[{"option":"Tertiary","bool":true},{"option":"Quaternary","bool":false},{"option":"Primary","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary","bool":false},{"option":"Simple","bool":false}]},{"id":175,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which are the most abundant cells of the human body?","answers":[{"option":"Red blood cells","bool":true},{"option":"White blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Cells of bone marrow","bool":false}]},{"id":176,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Riboflavin produces which coenzyme?","answers":[{"option":"Sulfur","bool":false},{"option":"Coenzyme A","bool":false},{"option":"FMN","bool":true},{"option":"NADP","bool":false},{"option":"NAD","bool":false}]},{"id":177,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Enzymes involved in the electron transport chain are located in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Inner mitochondrial membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Matrix of mitochondria","bool":false},{"option":"Cytosol","bool":false},{"option":"Cytoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Outer mitochondrial membrane","bool":false}]},{"id":178,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which structure contains preganglionic axons which synapse with postganglionic axons in the\r\nsympathetic chain and then pass into the anterior ramus?","answers":[{"option":"Greater splanchnic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Least splanchnic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser splanchnic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"White rami communicantes","bool":true},{"option":"Grey rami communicantes","bool":false}]},{"id":179,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Falak had a fracture in the midclavicular region. This region falls in which plane?","answers":[{"option":"Sagittal","bool":false},{"option":"Median","bool":false},{"option":"Coronal","bool":false},{"option":"Paramedian","bool":true},{"option":"Transverse","bool":false}]},{"id":180,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"The histological section of a tissue shows simple columnar epithelium with many finger-like projections on the apical surface. Where is this type of epithelium found?","answers":[{"option":"Intestinal wall","bool":true},{"option":"Ureter","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory tract","bool":false},{"option":"Esophagus","bool":false}]},{"id":181,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding the Na+/K+ pump?","answers":[{"option":"2Na+ out, 3K+ in","bool":false},{"option":"2Na+ in, 3K+ out","bool":false},{"option":"3Na+ out, 2K+ in","bool":true},{"option":"2Na+ in, 3K+ in","bool":false},{"option":"3Na+ in, 2K+ out","bool":false}]},{"id":182,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the movement of fingers away from the neutral position called?","answers":[{"option":"Flexion","bool":false},{"option":"Opposition","bool":false},{"option":"Abduction","bool":true},{"option":"Extension","bool":false},{"option":"Adduction","bool":false}]},{"id":183,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"What is the type of signaling in which the signaling factors produce an effect on the cell from which they are produced called?","answers":[{"option":"Integrin signaling","bool":false},{"option":"Paracrine signaling","bool":false},{"option":"Direct signaling","bool":false},{"option":"Endocrine signaling","bool":false},{"option":"Autocrine signaling","bool":true}]},{"id":184,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Hypoxia means a decrease in oxygen delivery to tissues. Which of the following can cause hypoxia and eventually lead to the decreased aerobic oxidative respiration?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiorespiratory failure","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease oxygen carrying capacity of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Ischemia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon monoxide poisoning","bool":true}]},{"id":185,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Two drugs act on the same organ or tissue and activate different receptors that produce different responses. Which type of antagonism is this?","answers":[{"option":"Physiological","bool":true},{"option":"Pharmacological","bool":false},{"option":"Chemical","bool":false},{"option":"Dispositional","bool":false},{"option":"Competitive","bool":false}]},{"id":186,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2020","question":"Which is the component of holoenzyme that is used in transcription?","answers":[{"option":"Beta factor","bool":false},{"option":"Promotor region","bool":false},{"option":"Cofactor","bool":false},{"option":"Sigma factor","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha factor","bool":false}]}]
export default arr